There will be greed. There will be vengeance.
There Will Be Blood is a drama film directed by Paul Thomas Anderson.
Ruthless silver miner, turned oil prospector, Daniel
Plainview, moves to oil-rich California.
Using his son to project a trustworthy, family-man image, Plainview cons local
landowners into selling him their valuable properties for a pittance.
However, local preacher Eli Sunday suspects Plainview's motives and intentions,
starting a slow-burning feud that threatens both their lives.
Daniel Plainview, played by Daniel Day-Lewis.
Paul Sunday / Eli Sunday, played by Paul Dano.
Henry, played by Kevin J. O'Connor.
Fletcher Hamilton, played by Ciarán Hinds.
H.W. Plainview, played by Dillon Freasier.
Elizabeth, played by Hope Elizabeth Reeves.
There Will Be Blood is a 2007 American epic period drama film co-produced, written and
directed by Paul Thomas Anderson, loosely based on the 1927 novel Oil!
by Upton Sinclair.
It stars Daniel Day-Lewis, Paul Dano, Kevin J.
O'Connor, Ciarán Hinds, and Dillon Freasier.
The film follows silver miner-turned-oilman Daniel Plainview (Day-Lewis) as he embarks on a ruthless
quest for wealth during the Californian oil boom in the late 19th and early 20th centuries.
Development on There Will Be Blood began after writer Eric Schlosser
purchased the film rights to Sinclair's novel in 2004.
It was acquired by Ghoulardi Film Company, Paramount Vantage and Miramax Films
after Anderson completed the first draft of the film's screenplay.
Day-Lewis immediately joined the project while Dano, who initially signed on for a smaller
role, took on a starring role after replacing Kel O'Neill during filming.
Principal photography began in June 2006 and lasted until that September,
with filming locations including Los Angeles and Marfa, Texas.
The film's music was composed by Radiohead guitarist Jonny Greenwood.
There Will Be Blood premiered at Fantastic Fest in Austin on September 29, 2007.
It was first theatrically released in New York City and Los Angeles on December
26 and in selected international markets on January 25, 2008.
It grossed $76.1 million worldwide and received acclaim from critics, with praise for the
cinematography, Anderson's direction, screenplay, music, and performances of Day-Lewis and Dano.
The National Board of Review, the American Film Institute and the National Society of
Film Critics named There Will Be Blood one of the top-ten films of 2007.
The film was nominated for eight awards at the 80th Academy Awards, winning two (Best Actor for
Day-Lewis and Best Cinematography for Elswit) and received numerous other accolades.
It has since been widely regarded as Paul Thomas Anderson's magnum opus, as well
as one of the greatest films of the 21st century and of all time.
The film explores themes of california, petrol, sibling
relationship, based on novel or book, capitalism.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking.